Bruce H. Maddock Papers
Bruce H. Maddock Papers
1943-1988
Maddock, Bruce H.
0.5 linear ft.
Personal patents, writings, and schematics from Union Carbide Plastics Division employee Bruce H. Maddock.
5120174
Biographical History
Bruce H. Maddock was a key figure in the development of processes and equipment for extrusion of thermoplastics. He joined the Bakelite Company in 1936. In 1939 the company was acquired by Union Carbide, and Maddock remained with the company until his retirement in 1974. He is credited with numerous important developments and was the author of a many important technical and research papers. An active member of the Society of Plastics Engineers (SPE), he received both their Engineering and Technology Award (1982) and International Award (1988). In 1997 he was inducted into the Plastics Hall of Fame.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Bruce H. Maddock Papers are divided into three series. Patents contains both Canadian and United States patents granted to Maddock for his work. Writings contains works by Maddock, both published and unpublished, about plastics extrusion. Miscellaneous includes two clippings of articles relating to plastics extrusion, not written by Maddock; one list of Maddock's patents and publications; and a schematic depicting a plastics mixing screw.
Arrangement of the Collection
Arranged alphabetically, and chronologically within folders.
Subject and Genre Headings
Plastics; Maddock, Bruce H.; Union Carbide Corporation.; Plastics -- Extrusion.; Plastics industry and trade.; Thermoplastics.; Patents.; Technical drawings.; Typescripts.; Clippings (information artifacts)
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Nancy Maddock, 2018.
Inventory
- Patents
  - Canadian, 1960 (Box 1)
    Canadian Patent no. 608,466.
  - United States, 1958-1973 (Box 1)
    United States Patents, nos. 2,834,054; 2,993,875; 3,032,822; 3,846,192; 3,730,492; 3,756,574. Some include correspondence informing Maddock of the patent's granting.
- Writings
  - Typescripts, 1943-1971; undated; 4 folders; articles and papers by Maddock (Box 1)
  - Publications, 1952-1988; undated; 6 folders; clippings and reprints, one article in Japanese (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous
  - Clippings, 1984-1989; one item cites Maddock (Box 1)
  - "Patents and publications" list, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Schematic of 4.5-inch mixing screw, 1971 (Box 1)